# KALOYAN DIMITROV

k.y.dimitrov@outlook.com | (+44) 7549 141599 | www.linkedin.com/in/kal-dimitrov

# **PROFILE**

A Computer Science graduate with a global perspective, hailing from Bulgaria and currently living, working, and studying in the UK since 2016. Valuing reliability, integrity, and sustainable development when facing challenges, passionate about technology and its potential to improve lives, it is a mission of mine to contribute to technology sector by creating original and memorable experiences while remaining committed to ethical practices, innovation, and responsible technological advancement.

# **SKILLS**

Soft: Teamwork, Problem-solver, Flexible, Creative, Proactive. User-Oriented, Hard-Working

Technical: Python, SQL, R, Full-stack, Java, C++, C#

Languages: English (Fluent), Bulgarian (Native), Russian (Basic), German (Basic)

Software Experience: Visual Studio, Visual Paradigm, SSMS, SSRS, PowerBI, IntelliJ IDEA, CLion and more

# **EDUCATION**

# City, University of London

# BSc (Hons), Computer Science with Games Technology with Placement

Sep 2019 - Jul 2024

# Final Year

- Relevant coursework in Advanced Games Technology, Functional Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Agents and Multi-Agent Systems, Computer Graphics
- Technical Skills: C++, Haskell, Python

# Placement Year

- Soft Skills: Critical Thinking, Business Intelligence, Data Analysis
- Technical Skills: SQL, R, Excel

# Second Year

- Relevant coursework in Object-Oriented Analysis and Design, Data Structures and Algorithms, C++, Computer Networks, Team Project, Games Technology
- Technical Skills: C++, UML

# First Year

- Relevant coursework in Algorithms, Data Structures, Data Modelling, Object-Oriented Programming, CPU Scheduling, 2D Computer Game, Website
- Technical Skills: Java, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, jQuerry, Bootstrap, Bash/Shell, Microsoft Office

# Wimbledon School of English, London, England

Oct 2018

Academic IELTS: Grade 6

- Listening, Reading, Writing, Reading
- Equivalent: A-levels

# Vocational School "Simeon Veliki", Shumen, Bulgaria

Sep 2011 - May 2015

BTEC Level 3 in Business Informatics

- Framework Levels: RQF Level 3, SCQF Level 6, CQFW Level 3
- Equivalent: A-levels
- Technical Skills: C++ Basics, MS Office

# **PROJECTS**

# Clty, University of London | Computer Graphics | Star Trek Route Game

Feb 2023 - Apr 2023

- Designed and devised an interactive demonstration of a racing game for the holodeck simulation aboard the USS Enterprise with OpenGL 4.0 and C++.
- Accomplished a Catmull-Rom spline with C continuity to define the track, ensuring smooth transitions between control points.
- Accomplished camera views using enumerations and switches in C++, utilizing TNB-frame and Frenet-Serret formulae to enable players to experience first-person, third-person, side-view, top-down, and free-camera perspectives.

# Clty, University of London | Introduction to Al | Natural Disaster Prediction

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

- Pioneered an approach to predicting natural disasters by examining and preprocessing a big dataset with python, resulting in some accurate predictions of time, location, and type of disaster.
- Delivered a well-described dataset and conducted exploratory analysis with python for feature selection.
- Performed interpolation to handle missing values for some features with python and incremented the dataset by determining geolocation of events.
- Managed the standardized data and calculated a measure of the total impact of disasters. This facilitated analysis with neural networks and one hot encoder.

# Clty, University of London | Team Project | BAPERS software

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021

- Adopted roles of a system designer, analyst and tester responsible for elicitation of customer requirements, analysis and specification, system design process and writing test plans, testing system and its components for a team of 7.
- Produced two detailed reports, one outlining the requirements and another the system design to devise the software architecture. Designed multiple diagrams, including Use-Case, Class, and Deployment diagrams, to provide UML documentation.
- Conducted thorough internal testing as part of a 7-member team to guarantee the dependability and resilience of the system.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Epsom and St Helier University Hospitals Data Analyst NHS Trust, London, England

Jun 2023 – Present Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

- Mined and formatted data from over 15 primary and secondary sources for statistical analysis, enhancing
  efficiency of data processing workflows leading to a 25% reduction in data preprocessing time, benefiting multiple
  clinical departments.
- Analysed and interpreted trends and patterns in over 50 data sets, enhancing diagnostic support and identifying 5+ process improvements in clinical areas, leading to a 15% increase in diagnostic accuracy and efficiency.
- Completed daily tasks related to data analysis, including mining data with SQL, producing SSRS reports, and analysing data with PowerBI.
- Led on and contributed to projects for clinical areas, providing digital analytic services with SSMS and SSRS to front-line clinicians.
- Implemented and optimized use of new technologies and processes, leading to a 10% increase in team efficiency and a 5% reduction in project delivery times.
- Generated various reports for clinical colleagues and developed procedural documentation for several daily and monthly tasks.
- Took part in daily group meetings pertaining to the NHS and relevant news.

# Bright Network, London, England

# **Technology Intern**

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

- Adopted role of a Product Manager for a large UK Bank, developed a plan with MS Office to release Facial Verification into customer banking application sign-in process.
- Delivered Project summary, User story summary, Project management plan and Communications plan documents using MS Office.

# Self Employed, London, England

# Handyman/Multi-Trader

Aug 2017 - Sep 2019

 Managed and completed over 100+ jobs as a Handyman and Multi-trader for various private clients and agencies, achieving a 95% satisfaction rate involving diverse tasks showcasing versatility and adaptability.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Vocational School "Simeon Veliki"

Certificate of Vocational Education (Business Informatics Specialist) | May 2015 – Present

# **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

# Strategic Gaming:

Passionate about strategy and simulation games, honing critical thinking and problem-solving skills in dynamic, virtual environments.

# Physical Fitness:

Regularly visit gym to maintain physical health, discipline, and resilience; value importance of mental and physical balance.

# **Urban Exploration:**

Enjoy long walks to explore and appreciate city's architecture and culture, fostering a keen sense of observation and mindfulness.

# Social Engagement:

Somewhat participating in community events and group activities, emphasizing the importance of collaboration, communication, and understanding diverse perspectives.

# Hands-on Builder:

Passionate about construction and DIY projects, reflecting problem-solving skills, attention to detail, and ability to transform concepts into tangible outcomes.